Finding Aid for Washtenaw Council on Alcoholism records, 1966-1988
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Washtenaw Council on Alcoholism records 1966-1988
Washtenaw Council on Alcoholism.
0.7 linear feet
88507 Bj 2
Washtenaw County, Michigan, citizens group concerned with alcohol-related problems. History, administrative records, and slides.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records came from the organization (donor no. 7488 ) in 1988.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
In 1956, a group of citizens concerned about alcohol-related problems organized the Washtenaw Committee on Alcoholism (WCA), Incorporated as the Washtenaw County Council on Alcoholism in 1960, the Council was renamed several times, eventually gaining its present name in 1972.
Originally offering limited informational and referral services to the public through a voluntary staff, the WCA was recognized in 1976 as having one of the most comprehensive alcoholic treatment programs in the United States. Included in the Council's programs are the Substance Abuse Program offered to junior high school classes, Family Group Therapy Program, workshops, seminars and in-service training.
The Washtenaw Council on Alcoholism records consist of reports, minutes, newsletters, printed materials, correspondence, and slides dating from 1966 to 1988. The files are arranged alphabetically by topic and chronologically within each folder. The History file provides useful background information about the organization. Also included are various reports and minutes that record the concerns and plans of the organization. The "Slides" folders contain visual images pertaining to the programs the WCA offers to the public.
Subjects:
Alcoholism.; Washtenaw County (Mich.)
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Alcoholism.; Washtenaw Council on Alcoholism (Mich.)
Genre Terms:
Slides.
- Organizational records
  - Accreditation Correspondence, February 1975-December 1986 (Box 1)
  - Activity Reports, July 1975-June 1983 (Box 1)
  - Alcoholism Today Newsletters, January 1974-April 1976 (Box 1)
  - Annual Meeting Minutes, January 1974-April 1987 (Box 1)
  - Annual Reports, 1973-1982 (Box 1)
  - Antabuse, 1961-1969 (Box 1)
  - Audit Reports, June 1973-June 1975 (Box 1)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, March-June 1968 (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees Meeting Minutes, January 1973-November 1987 (Box 1)
  - Clippings, ca. 1970 (Box 1)
  - Community Relations, February 1986-May 1987 (Box 1)
  - Constitution and By-laws, undated (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, December 1967-October 1982 (Box 1)
  - Financial Reports, September 1985-September 1987 (Box 1)
  - Form Letters, July 1974-February 1982 and undated (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, January-October 1974 (Box 1)
  - General Meeting Minutes, January-February 1968 (Box 1)
  - History, 1986 (25th anniversary) (Box 1)
  - Mission Statements, Policies, Organizational Charts, undated (Box 1)
  - National Council on Alcoholism Correspondence, April-August 1966 (Box 1)
  - Nominating Committee, February 1971 (Box 1)
  - President's Reports, 1971-1987 (Box 1)
  - Printed Materials, undated (Box 1)
  - Services for Problem Drinkers Project, October 1974 (Box 1)
  - Slides, ca. 1980, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Staff Reports, 1979-1988 (Box 1)
  - Studies, 1974-1987 (Box 1)
  - Treatment Committee, March 1975 (Box 1)